

BILLY WITANTO

As a former scientist, I possess a keen interest in statistics and data analysis. I have firsthand experience recognizing the pivotal role of data in decision making and policy formulation. I prioritize delivering accurate, unbiased insights to drive actionable results. I also value the role of intuition and logical thinking in refining the insights gained. I am ambitious, disciplined yet versatile, with structural thinking and growth mindset.

Phone: (+62)822-9160-4432 LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/billywitanto/
Email: billywitanto/
GitHub: https://github.com/b1llywitant0

WORK EXPERIENCE

Digital Marketing Analyst Supervisor PT. Central Mega Kencana

DKI Jakarta, Indonesia October 2022 – Now

Responsible to analysis of digital marketing-related campaigns, which include but not limited to media placement of ads, website & search engine optimization, and social media.

Job Responsibilities:

- Participating and contributing to the planning stage of marketing campaigns. Several tasks in this scope
 are conducting market research, translating the business goals into metrics and KPI, defining the proper
 methodology for data collection and analysis, defining customer journey and implementing tracking
 system, orchestrating A/B testing, etc.
- Maintaining good data governance and assessing the quality and validity of data retrieved by conducting data wrangling and exploratory data analysis, as necessary.
- Evaluating the performance of the marketing campaigns and contributing to the future campaigns' improvements by giving actionable insights using the combination of data driven and intuitive/logic approach.
- Translating the evaluation results into easily-digested reports for higher ups, yet still detailed enough for evaluation of the relevant team.
- Keep up with the trends and best practices in the industry and conducting competitors' review.

Tools: (General) Python, Microsoft Office, Google Data Studio, BigQuery, (Ads) Meta Ads Manager, Google Ads Manager, TikTok Ads Manager, (SEO & Website) SEMrush, Google Analytics 4 (GA4), Google Search Console, Google Trends, Google Tag Manager, (Social Media) Fanpage Karma, Brand24

Personal Contributions:

- Creating naming convention for more efficient data analysis and successfully reducing the data cleaning time significantly. For examples: UTM naming, campaign/ad group/ads naming, hashtags, etc.
- Initiating and supervising the implementation of data warehousing for ads data using BigQuery for more automatic process and less of human error. Still on going.
- Creating Python scripts for semi-automatic data validity checking and data visualization, reducing the reporting time.
- Creating Python scripts for automatic saving process of website data from Universal Analytics (UA) and/or GA4 to Google Spreadsheet using API.
- Creating Python scripts for leads distribution system to their nearby stores based on Haversine formula.
- Creating new reporting format with proper metrics focusing on generating actionable insights, not just presenting numbers.
- Initiating in-depth analysis and defining the tracking system to determine the digital marketing contribution to the sales.
- Improving the cost efficiency and performance metrics of ads campaigns through recommendations: CPM, CPC, CPL, CTR, CVR.

Research Assistant Eijkman Institute of Molecular Biology

DKI Jakarta, Indonesia May 2018 – September 2021

Job Responsibilities:

- Conducting literature study to deepen the understanding about the topics of ongoing and/or upcoming research projects and to collect supporting data/references needed as the foundation of the research;
- Collecting data from biological samples through lab experiments;
- Managing data collected using Microsoft Excel, that also includes data entry process;
- Analyzing data with statistical method using SPSS and/or R;
- Assisting senior researchers in any research process as needed, such as proposal writing, statistical analysis design, paper/report writing, presentation preparation with data visualization, etc.

Personal Contributions:

- Responsible for the methodology statistical and data analysis of <u>Host Factor in The Natural History of</u> Chronic Hepatitis B: Role of Genetic Determinants.
- Travel grant award recipient for chosen abstracts (poster) in APASL Bali 2020. Poster.
- Best poster at Kongres Nasional & Pertemuan Ilmiah Nasional PGI-PEGI-PPHI Palembang 2019. Poster.

EDUCATION

Purwadhika Digital Technology School Job Connector: Data Science and Machine Learning

DKI Jakarta, Indonesia October 2021 – April 2022

- Final Score: 86.78 of 100. Full-time bootcamp of data science.
- Curriculum: Programming Fundamental using Python and Visual Studio Code; Data and Statistical Analysis using SQL, Jupyter Notebook, and Tableau; Machine Learning Methodologies.

Tools: (Programming & Data Analysis) Python, MySQL, VS Code, (Data Visualization) Tableau

Surya University Bachelor of Science

Tangerang Selatan, Indonesia August 2013 – September 2017

- GPA: 3.74 of 4.00. Major in Biology, Biotechnology.
- TEMPO-Surya University Scholarship throughout the study period with minimum required GPA per year.
- Dean's Honor Lists throughout the study period: 2013/2014, 2014/2015, 2015/2016, 2016/2017.
- Active as lecturer- and laboratory-assistant in several subjects, also in several mini-projects.

PROJECTS, SKILLS, & INTERESTS

You can find most of my projects in my GitHub page. A few examples of my POC projects:

- 1. Supervised classification analysis: https://github.com/b1llywitant0/Technical-Tests
- 2. Supervised regression analysis: https://github.com/b1llywitant0/Philadelphia-Property-Value-Prediction
- 3. Supervised time series forecasting analysis: https://github.com/b1llywitant0/Time-Series-FB-PROPHET
- 4. Supervised sentiment analysis: https://github.com/b1llywitant0/NLP-Sentiment-Analysis
- 5. SQL exercises: https://github.com/b1llywitant0/SQL-Exercises

Hard Skills:

- Research and literature study: Expert
- General programming: Intermediate
- Data wrangling: Expert
- Exploratory data analysis (EDA): Expert
- Statistics: Intermediate
- · Machine learning: Beginner
- · Data visualization: Intermediate
- Writing: Expert
- Presentation: Expert

Soft Skills:

- Critical thinking
- Analytical thinking
- Structural thinking
- Growth mindset
- Time management
- Curiosity
- Teamwork
- Communication
- Problem solving

Languages: Bahasa (Native), English (Professional)

Domain Interests:

Marketing, Customer Relationship Management, Advertising, Website, User Behaviors, Data Pipeline and Storing